HECTOR AHOW

Junior Data Analyst

Barcelona, Venezuela hectorahow@gmail.com +58.414.806.1978 hectorportfolio.github.io

OBJECTIVE

Junior data analyst position seeking to leverage my mechanical engineering background and analytical skills to extract insights from data and solve complex business problems

SKILLS

- Data analysis
- Data visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn)
- Python (Pandas, NumPy, Sklearn, Haversine)
- SQL (MySQL)
- POWER BI
- Web Scrapping
- Microsoft Office
- Communication and Teamwork

PROJECTS

RESTAURANTS SCRAPING AND DATA ANALYSIS - NOV 2023

This project aims to analyze restaurant ratings and reviews into customer sentiment and restaurant performance. It involves scraping restaurant data from the Google Maps API, analyzing rating distribution, identifying trends, sentiment analysis, and creating visualizations in **POWER BI** to present the findings.

UBER DATA ANALYSIS - SEP 2023

Analyzed and cleaned 200,000 Uber travel data in New York using Pandas and NumPy. Visualize locations using Folium. Identified demand patterns to improve the efficiency of the Uber system based on the visualization with Matplotlib and Seaborn.

STOCK PRICE PREDICTOR - AUG 2023

Analyzed the last 7 years of market data using **Pandas** and **NumPy**. Getting stock prices using yfinance from Yahoo Finance. Created an artificial recurrent neural network (Long Short Term Memory) model to predict the closing price of Microsoft stock. Visualized data using Matplotlib, and Seaborn.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Project Manager. 2021 – Present. Remotely monitored and analyzed operational data of a boiler and chiller system (district energy system) for a building and condominium in Guelph, Canada, to support decision-making and actions on the system.

Piping Engineering. 2012 - 2021. Analyzed and cleaned raw material data. Automated the counting of materials and equipment for several projects in a spreadsheet, minimizing the execution time of this activity (previously performed manually).

Sales Engineer. 2004 – 2012. Controlled input and output data of the inventory of various equipment and products in a spreadsheet, for the creation of quotes based on the product available.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Mechanical Engineer | 1997 – 2003 | Barcelona, Venezuela

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native) English

HOBBIES Workout exercises, Soccer, Cooking, Barista